曾对这个世界有爱
和主人公们一同冒险的朋友们
让我们再度欢聚一堂
Why did humankind even bothered.
破坏与创造
You rack everything you've ever made, and start over.
人类为何一直重蹈覆辙
Like there'll be any different after that.
我真是无法理解
I supposed we're not good at facing our memories,
人类不擅长面对回忆
We'd rather kill the past.
所以美化它 夸大它
Find something worthwile among the rubble and build the future with that.
试图用怀念来包装疼痛来走出过去的阴霾
And that's the reason why you hide Mother?
你为什么要取回妈妈?
To kill the past?
也是出于怀念?
We were trying to rid ourselves of a more immediate problem.
我们是为了克服眼前的难题
You don't mean the stigma?
你指星痕?
But you're the one who brought that on yourself in the first place.
其实归根到底都是你们的错
I see.
这样啊
I guess you really do have a short memory.
看来你也无法面对回忆啊
No, not me.
不 我只是
You see, it is my choice to forget.
我只是忘记了我的选择
(两星期前)
Tseng! Look at this.
曾先生!快看这个
Hm?
嗯?
Found it.
我们找到了
Not a pretty sight, is it?
惨不忍睹是吗?
Who cares? Just get the damn thing.
谁关心?总之快一点吧
Reno, I'm counting on you.
雷诺 拜托了
You got it.
收到
Whoa!
喂喂喂!
Senpai, hurry!
前辈 快离开!
Senpai!
前辈!
Who the hell is that?
谁啊?
Elena!
伊利娜!
Go! Get out!
你快走!
Tsengsan!
曾先生!
You are going to give her back eventually.
你是要让她犹豫
The Lifestream.
生命之河
That's what we call the river of life that circles our planet
那是围绕着星球的生命之河
giving life to the world and everything in it.
星球和她滋养的万物生灵的源头
The Shinra Electric Power Company discovered a way
神罗公司发现了把生命之河
to use the Lifestream as an energy source.
当作能源使用的方法
Because of Shinra's energy, we were able to live very comfortable lives.
多亏了它 使我们的生活变的非常富裕
But wasn't that because we were taking away from the planet's life?
但是这种方法会剥削星球的生命?
A lot of people thought so.
也有很多人这么认为
Shinra used their power to try and stop anybody who got in their way.
神罗对于反对他的人们使用武力镇压
Shinra had a special group of warriors called SOLDIER.
神罗麾下有一批特种兵名为战士
And all the SOLDIERs had Jenova cells put inside them.
是很久以前从天而降
Jenova was a calamity that fell from the sky a long, long time ago
以毁灭星球为己任的灾厄
and tried to destroy the planet.
杰诺娃细胞的移植产物
Anyway, there was one SOLDIER named Sephiroth
有位名叫萨菲罗斯的士兵
who was better than the rest.
非常优秀的战士
But when he found out about the terrible experiments that made him
不过从他得知了自己诞生于恐怖实验的事实后
he began to hate Shinra.
因此对神罗怀恨在心
And then, over time, he began to hate everything.
久而久之 他开始憎恨这一切的一切
Shinra and the people against them.
憎恨神罗和反对它的人们
Sephiroth, who hated the planet so much
萨菲罗斯憎恨到
he wanted to make it go away.
不惜一切摧毁星球
And the people who tried to stop him.
很多人竭力阻止萨菲罗斯
There were a lot of battles.
带来了无数战斗
For every battle, there was more sadness.
战争与悲剧也形影不离
Someone I love went back to the Lifestream too.
我最喜爱的人也化作了生命之河
And then, it came.
终于在那一天
The chosen day.
命运之日
In the end, the planet itself had to make the battles stop for good.
星球用自身的力量平息了一切干戈
The planet used the Lifestream as a weapon
星球把生命之河用作武器
and when it burst out of the earth
喷出地面的生命之河
all the fighting, all the greed and sadness
将纷争 野望 悲伤
everything was washed away.
统统吞噬
"Sadness was the price to see it end. "
"我们用悲伤划上了句点"
It's been two years since they told me that.
这样的说法是从两年前开始的
Move it, move it.
往那移 往那移
Whoa.
哇
Sis, let's go.
姐姐 走吧
Yeah.
嗯
But it looks like the planet is a lot angrier than we thought.
不过星球它远比我们想像的更要愤怒
They call it geostigma.
星痕群后遗症
Well, Marlene? How does it look?
我说 马琳?变什么样了?
Please. Please don't take Denzel away.
求求您 请不要带走丹泽尔
"The commission report release this morning has reveal"
"根据调查委今晨颁布的报告"
"That lifestream concentration at the atmosphere"
"大气中的生命之河浓度"
"Has been drop to a mere hundred of a levels 2 years ago. "
"仅为2年前的百分之一 "
"However, the concentration remains toxic"
"已经降至对人体毫无影响的程度"
"Around the Shinra Company main building as well as the company's mako reactors.
"然而 神罗公司大厦以及所属的周边地区"
"He's not here anymore.
这里人去楼空了
"To prevent the onset of Geostigma"
"依然屹立于危险浓度中"
"The commission does advice that you stay away from these facilities"
"为了防患星痕群后遗症 请远离存在隐患的设施"
"And the surrounding areas. "
"委员会如上警告"
"Next up. Should Shinra be held financial responsible for the crisis? "
接下来报导神罗公司被追究的赔偿
Cloud, where is he now?
克劳德 你在哪里?
Strife Delivery Service. You name it, we ship
您好 是冲突快递 我们服务广泛
May I ask who's calling?
请问是哪位?
Yeah, I remember you.
嗯 当然记得你
You got a call from Reno. He's in Healin.
雷诺从圆球别墅来电话了
Says he's got work for you.
他要委托你工作
Cloud, how have you been?
克劳德 你还好吗?
You have no more messages
讯息完毕
《最终幻想7：圣子降临》
Hey, Kadaj? Is that where Big Brother lives?
我说卡达裘?那就是哥哥的城镇吗?
Yeah.
嗯
Think he'll be happy to see us?
你想他会欢迎我们吗?
Not a chance. Don't cry, Yazoo.
不可能的 可别哭啊 亚祖
But Mother's with him?
但妈妈和他在一起吧
Maybe not.
这可难说
Oh, don't cry, Loz.
别哭啊 罗兹
Look, here he comes.
瞧啊 说人到就到
Where's Mother?
妈妈在哪?
We know you hid her, Brother.
被哥哥给藏起来了吧
Don't tell me you're leading me on?
难到 你骗我?
Because I think you do have Mother there.
妈妈果然还在你们手中吧
No need to shout.
别吼啊
Put the president on.
懒得和你说了
You're starting to bother me.
换社长接
Don't run away.
不是逃避了吧
Hey, it's me, Barret!
噢 我是巴雷特!
I did it! A new oil field! OILFIELD!
老子成功了!找到新油田了!油 田
A huge one, too!
超级大!
And we're sticking to plan, so soon I'll be able to come visit Marlene!
工作差不多完成后 不久就去见马琳
Tell her for me! See ya!
帮我问候一下!拜啦!
Reno called again.
雷诺又打电话来了
He says to hurry, but he sounded kind of strange
催你赶快去 总觉得有点怪怪的
Be careful, okay?
你自己要当心啊?
Okay, so you're good.
好的 果然有两下子
Yeah, Rude, looking sharp!
鲁德 有型啊!
Just as expected from an exSOLDIER.
真不愧是自封的前战士
You haven't rusted a bit.
身手依旧不凡
Is that you, Rufus? You've got no luck either
你是路法斯?你也真是倒楣啊
The day of the explosion What do you want?
那天我 找我有什么事?
I managed to get out Who were the guys that attacked me?
大楼坍塌前总算是 袭击我的人是谁?
before it colla I'm leaving.
我要走了
We need your assistance.
助我一臂之力
Not interest I acknowledge that Shinra
没兴趣 我们神罗公司
owes the planet a lot.
欠世界一笔大债
It goes without saying that my company and I
害得世界惨淡而寥落
are the ones who put the world in the sorry state it's in.
人们把责任推给我们也合乎情理
So we feel we have a responsibility to set things right.
于是这笔债非还不可
I'm still out here!
开门啊!
We've already taken the first step
作为第一步棋
by conducting an investigation in Sephiroth's wake.
我们调查起萨菲罗斯遗留的影响
It's been 2 years,
过去两年了
now that that the world is on the speed again,
世界迈出了复兴的一步
what's the threat now?
什么构成了最大威胁?
Well, that one's easy, Geostigma.
没错 是万恶的星痕群后遗症
And we have to think Sephiroth is the one responsible.
我们认为原因出在萨菲罗斯身上
The people blame Mako energy, Mako reactors,
世人认为魔晃炉 魔晃能源
even the Lifestream for causing the stigma
以及生命之河是星痕的原因正在
However, isn't it wrong to put a blame on it?
我看未必吧?
The Lifestream existed as long as the Planet and. . .
生命之河与星球一起诞生
. . . even Mako evergy has been part of our life for 40 years.
魔晃能源更有40多年的利用史
And yet there's no mention about stigma in recorded history.
尽管如此 星痕在历史上从未有过登场
So, what happen during our time to change all that?
那么我们这一代和有不同寻常?
I can only think of one thing.
想不出别的了
Sephiroth's awaken.
是萨菲罗斯的存在
Sephiroth is dead.
萨菲罗斯死了
Of course, but what about his mind?
他的精神去了哪里?
What if somehow he dissolve into the Lifestream coursing with the Planet undiffuse.
溶解在了生命之河中倘若它未扩散而巡行在星球
那会怎样
I know, it's merely my speculation.
当然这终究是我的猜测
But, there are possibilities right?
却也不无可能性
And we can't cure the stigma until we know the truth.
发现真相才能推动星痕的治愈
So we took the first step, and went to look for traces of Sephiroth.
于是我们调查了萨菲罗斯留下的蛛丝马迹
Do you by any chance, still remember where is it?
先前 你还记得?
At the Northern Cave!
在北方的大空洞!
What do you think we found?
你猜发现了什么?
We didn't find anything. You can relax.
在那儿什么都没有 放心好了
However, not all went as planned.
不过却发生了出乎我们意料之外的事
We were interrupted.
他们出现了
Tsengsan!
曾先生!
Kadaj's gang.
卡达裘一伙儿人
Kadaj?
卡达裘?
Really, what could they be thinking?
他连你也不会放过?
What does that have to do with me?
我想你与他们有交过手?
You are going to give her back eventually.
迟早会物归原主
Your ties with Sephiroth run as deep as our too Cloud.
你与我们一样与萨菲罗斯有很深的过往
And if Kadaj goal is to prepare for an imminent occasion
如果卡达裘的目的 是给来临的那一刻做铺垫
We should be prepared for the upcoming threat.
我们无疑是最大的障碍
Prepare?
铺垫?
Sephiroth
萨菲罗斯
resurrection.
卷土重来
Are you done talking?
话说完了?
Let's get things clear.
那么回归正题
In order to battle with Kadaj, we need someone with your expertise.
为了与卡达裘他们抗衡 我们需要你
Will you join us?
何不并肩作战?
SOLDIER member, Cloud.
前战士克劳德
Former.
那是我自称罢了
What's this stuff about 'Mother'?
妈妈是是什么意思?
Beats me. Didn't Kadaj mention anything to you?
不清楚 卡达裘说了什么吗?
Rufus.
路法斯
Are you hiding something from me?
你隐瞒了什么?
I never keep a secret, especially from a comrade.
你我站在同一战线 我怎么会隐瞒
I'm sure you wanted to learn more about the stigma?
关于星痕的情报想必你也需要?
Obviously for the sake of those orphan you live with.
为了生活在同一屋檐下的孤儿们
Don't you want to see the smile of the children?
难道你不想让那些孩子们重拾笑容吗?
All we want in the end is to rebuild our world, Cloud.
我们的最终目的是重建世界 克劳德
But I Come on, Cloud.
我 拜托了 克劳德
Together, we can rebuild Shinra!
让神罗公司东山再起!
Not interested.
没兴趣
Reno! Reno!
雷诺!雷诺!
Does Cloud live here?
克劳德住在这里吗?
I guess he does.
好像是吧
What's this?
什么东西?
It's just like Denzel. Is Cloud sick?
和丹泽尔一样 克劳德也生病了吗?
Why didn't he just say something?
为什么不告诉我?
Did he leave because he's sick?
是因为生病才离开吗?
He wants to fight alone.
他要独自去战斗
Fight? No.
战斗? 不对
I don't think he will.
他根本没有斗志
Tifa?
蒂法?
Let's go back, Marlene?
我们回去吧 马琳?
No! I wanna see Cloud!
不要! 我要见克劳德!
I guess you're right.
就是
It'd be nice to see him, huh? Yeah.
想见他啊? 嗯
Hey, what should we do when he gets here?
那 见面之后怎么办?
We'll all go home!
带他回家!
Before that, we'll lecture him!
不过在那之前先念他一顿!
Agreed!
赞成!
Now we just have to find Tseng and Elena.
接下来要找主任和伊利娜
The other employees give you any leads?
其他社员提供的情报呢?
Nothing yet.
暂时没有收获
Who have thought, Shinra's employee return to work.
原来的社员来齐了这么多真是超出预料
Now that's dedicate. I'm telling you this going to be a fresh start.
我超感动的 我看能重新来过
Well, those who alive have a lot to atone for.
赎罪的重任落在活下来的人身上
It's been 2 years already, right?
过去两年了 嗯?
It seems a lot longer than that.
才两年啊
What a nightmare huh?
那简直是噩梦
The world was almost done for.
世界险些灭亡
And we're a part of it.
我们神罗惹的祸
Seriously though, how we're supposed to atone for that?
说真的 我们要赎多少罪啊?
Too bad the directors not around.
少了主任果然很头疼啊
Elena too.
伊利娜也是
I hope they're still alive.
千万给我活的好好的
It's alright.
没问题
Tseng is just like the President. They always escape from the death god.
曾先生和社长一样 九死一生
I'm sure of that.
运气好的很
You got that right.
也是啊
Found you.
找到了
Church?
教堂?
Ah, I know that one.
哦 那个地方的
I'll be waiting.
嗯 我等你
Your call to Sector 7 cannot be reached at the moment.
您拨打七号街的电话暂时无法接通
Cloud, you rarely call back aren't you?
克劳德 真意外接到你的电话?
Anything happen?
出事了吗?
Cloud?
克劳德?
No it's not.
我不是
Who's this? Isn't this Cloud's phone?
你是谁?这是克劳德的电话吧?
I don't know.
不清楚
Who are you?
你是谁呢?
I don't know. Please, I don't know what to do, I can't do this.
不清楚 我不知道怎么办好
Are you crying?
你在哭吗?
What happen? Are you okay?
怎么了 你没事吗?
Cloud! Cloud! Where are you?
克劳德!克劳德!你在那吗?
Oi!
喂!
Are you alright?
没事吧?
I hate liars.
我讨厌说谎
I apologize. This time you'll get the truth.
是我不好 这次我会实话实说
The object you seek fell from the helicopter while we were running from you.
那东西在摆脱你们的途中从直升机上掉下去了
What a ridiculous story.
太失态了
Is that right?
真的吗?
I swear it.
我发誓
Then swear on these.
不妨向这个发誓
Why are you doing this? We need Mother's power.
你的目的是什么? 我需要妈妈的力量
The Reunion is coming and we need her.
为了再结合绝不能少了她
Reunion?
再结合?
My brothers and sisters who share Mother's cells will all assemble.
获得妈妈细胞的同伴齐聚一堂
And together, we'll take revenge on the planet.
然后向这星球报复
We've already sent out the invitations, but you know.
准备工作稳步进行着
Someone's gone and hidden the guest of honor.
你瞧 都怪某些人把妈妈藏了起来
Invitations?
准备?
The stigma. But you know all about that.
星痕 社长你也很清楚吧
Mother's memetic legacy lives on in the Lifestream and makes it happen.
这多亏在生命之河中 有妈妈的遗传意念在挣扎着
She does so much for us, and we don't even know where to find her.
再看看我们 居然不清楚妈妈在哪
But what can we do, we're just remnants of Mother's legacy.
丢死人了 但却无可奈何 谁让我们是区区意念体
Until we find Mother and receive her cells, we can't be whole again.
只有找到妈妈后分得细胞 我们才能够复原
Geostigma and a legacy aren't enough.
光有意念和星痕远谈不上准备充分
Not for a true Reunion.
为了完美的再结合
What do you mean?
你在说什么?
Mr. President, surely you've noticed?
社长 你早就查觉到了吧?
Sorry, sorry.
抱歉 抱歉
The stigma!
哇 星痕!
Can't you people just stay indoors?
别出门吓唬人啊?
Here.
这个
I said I'd live out both our lives.
我会连你的份好好活下去
Easier said than done.
虽然那时是这样决定
You wanna be in SOLDIER? Hang in there!
想成为战士啊?加把劲!
Hey, how're you doing?
喂 感觉如何?
What're you gonna do once we get to Midgar?
我说 到达米德加尔后 你怎么打算?
We're friends, right?
我们是朋友吧?
Old man, stop somewhere behind a rock.
大叔 找个岩石在后面停车
Cloud, wee getting off!
克劳德 我们下车!
My dreams and pride
我的荣耀和梦想
You can have them all.
全给你了
You're
你
the proof that I existed.
是我生命的见证
On that day, I swore I'll never forget.
那时候发誓过决不忘记
But, I
不过 我
Don't pretend you're sad.
别假装悲伤
Why tremble with anger that's not even there.
也别假装义愤填膺
Do you know why, Cloud?
你知道因为什么?克劳德
All you are, is an empty puppet.
因为你是 傀儡
Wanna play?
一起玩吧?
I guess that's a no.
哦 不要啊
Where's Mother?
妈妈呢?
It stinks.
好臭啊
Hey, where's Mother? There's no one here!
我说 妈妈呢 这里没有别人了!
Fine. Play with me.
那么一起玩吧
This'll be fun.
真令人期待
Tifa!
蒂法!
She's not here.
找错地方了吧
I'm not crying!
我没哭!
Got it. I'll bring it.
知道了 我带她去
Time to finish this.
继续
Cloud!
克劳德!
Run!
快逃啊!
About earlier, I'm sorry.
刚才抱歉了
Thank you.
谢谢你
My brother
弟弟
Isn't around anymore.
已经不在了
I see.
是吗
You've got the stigma too?
你也得了星痕吧?
Come on, they're gonna fix us.
来吧 有人能治好
Tifa?
蒂法?
Tifa!
蒂法!
You're late
你来得太晚了
Who did this?
谁干的?
He didn't say.
不认识的人
Marlene? !
马琳?
No
可恶
You're pretty heavy.
重死人了
You were living with some kids, right?
哥哥 你跟孩子们生活的吧?
They ain't here.
全不见了
Is that okay with you?
不担心吗?
I
我
You're a real handful.
真不坦白
Tifa said to take you home, kid.
蒂法要我带你过去
Hold on tight.
抓紧了
Who are these people that's going to fix us?
谁会治好我们?
I don't know.
不清楚
Anyone is fine.
嗯 管他是谁呢
So Big Brother was hiding it.
原来是哥哥藏的
This is the power of the Lifestream.
从生命之河中诞生的新力量
This materia will give us renewed power.
让魔石球赐给我们新能力
So, those were a gift from Mother?
那是妈妈留给我们的吧
Yea, it should be.
嗯 一定是
Then, Brother is hiding Mother too?
妈妈也被哥哥藏起来了?
No. It's that President guy.
不 是那个社长
Keeping things hidden is something Shinra's people are very good at
神罗公司一向喜欢把妈妈藏起来
Then we have to look everywhere that have to do with Shinra.
那不妨把神罗的相关建筑搜个遍
Pretty soon, we'll have plenty of helps.
嗯 更多伙伴会蜂拥而至
This is fun!
我好期待!
But first.
不过先要
We need to have a talk with Brother.
向哥哥发发牢骚
He likes to pretend as if he's not a part of the family.
装作自己是局外人
He makes me sad, really sad.
真令人悲哀
Right?
呐?
Reno and Rude are looking.
雷诺他们在四处打听
You have geostigma, don't you.
星痕群后遗症 对吧
So it's okay to just give up and die. Is that what you think?
死了也无所谓吗?
It knew it.
果然
There's no cure.
没有治愈的希望
That's not stopping Denzel from fighting.
不过 丹泽尔却从来不放弃
Don't run. Let's fight it together.
我们一起面对它不好吗
We can help each other, I know we can.
互相帮助 一起奋斗啊
Or do we have to be a real family for that to work?
不是真正的家人 果然不行呢
I
我可能
am not fit to help anyone.
谁也救不了
Not my family, not my friends.
家人也好 同伴也好
No one.
都救不了
Dillydally, shillyshally
拖拖拉拉
I think she wants you to move on.
要拖到什么时候啊
Did you find them?
还找不到吗?
Only a witness.
有目击者
Saw them being taken away.
说是被那帮家伙带走的
Where are they? The Forgotten City.
去了哪里? 遗忘之都
Their base.
他们老家
I've received a special power from Mother.
妈妈眷顾我一份特殊力量
The power to fight
星球作战的力量
against a planet that torments its people.
能与折磨人的罪魁
She gave this power to all her children.
其实你们也有这个能力
That's right.
没错
You and I are brethren.
我们是一家人
Brothers and sisters chosen
继承了溶解在生命之河中
when we inherited Mother's memetic legacy through the Lifestream.
妈妈遗传意念的被选中的一家人
But
不过
the planet doesn't like that.
星球在百般阻挠
It's trying to hold us back.
它试图停止我们成长
That's why it's been racking our bodies with pain, filling our hearts with doubt!
所以说你们遭受皮肉之苦痛不欲生!
I will heal you.
我来帮你们治好
Then we will go to Mother.
然后回到妈妈身边
We will join as a family and strike back at the planet!
一家人齐心协力报复星球
Do as I do.
跟着我做
Denzel.
丹泽尔
Denzel!
丹泽尔!
Mother, look.
妈妈 您瞧啊
All my new siblings.
多了这么多兄弟
They will keep me company until I found you.
直到与妈妈见面我也不会寂寞了
You came.
你终于来了
Even though you're about to break.
明明自己都快撑不住了 对吧
That's a good sign.
一定会好转的
I wanna ask something!
我问你!
Why exactly did you come here for?
为什么要来这里?
I think I want to be forgiven
我想想获得原谅
Yes, I want to be forgiven.
嗯 我想被原谅
By who?
被谁?
Glad you could make it.
你果然来了
I'm here for the kids.
我来接孩子们回家
See this man? He's our big brother.
这个人啊 是我们的哥哥
But you know,
不过呢
It's a shame
很可惜的是
He's a traitor.
他是叛徒
Cloud!
克劳德!
I really can't save anyone, right?
还真是救不了任何人
Vincent. What do you know about this?
文森特 怎样一回事?
I come here often.
我常来这里
I've seen what Kadaj's group is doing.
因而卡达裘们的一举一动我全看在眼里
The stigma.
所谓星痕
Inside our bodies, we all have a current like the Lifestream.
是在我们身体里有像生命之河潮流
When alien matter infests the body, this current is what fights it off.
排除体内异物的系统反应过剩所致
There's a flow through the body like the Lifestream
体内也有类似生命之河的循环
It fights against the invasion of harmful substances.
它与入侵的邪恶物质对峙
Harmful substances
邪恶物质
The Sephiroth gene. Jenova's memetic legacy.
萨菲罗斯因子 杰诺娃的遗传意念
Call it what you want.
随你怎么称呼
You're wellinformed.
好详细
Tseng and Elena.
曾和伊利娜
They were brought here halfdead.
奄奄一息着被搬到这里
They must have been brutally tortured.
想必是被严加拷问的后果
I did what I could to save them
救倒是救了
but it was ugly.
生死难说
Tortured?
拷问?
They had it coming.
自作自受
They got their hands on Jenova's head.
他们似乎把杰诺娃的人头弄到手了
Then the "Mother"Kadaj is looking for
卡达裘所找的妈妈是指?
Heaven's dark harbinger. The calamity, Jenova.
从天而降的凶神 杰诺娃
If they wanted to, they could make another Sephiroth.
用她造出第二个萨菲罗斯也不无可能
Kadaj
卡达裘
What is he?
什么人?
I'd rather not know.
我也不想知道
Marlene!
马琳!
Cloud! Denzel and Tifa!
克劳德!丹泽尔和蒂法她!
Tifa is all right.
蒂法没有事
I wanna talk to her!
我要跟蒂法说话!
Do you have it?
你有手机吗?
I can't believe it!
真不敢相信!
Vincent, will you take Marlene back to the bar?
文森特 帮我把马琳送到店里
I'm gonna go get some answers from Shinra.
我去找神罗他们
You know I can't. But
我不赞成这样做 可是
Cloud, that's enough!
够了 克劳德!
Why won't you listen to what we're trying to say?
为什么总是一意孤行?
Marlene, please give me some time.
马琳 再忍耐一会儿
There's a battle to be fought
我想战斗马上就会开始
but it's not as simple as just fighting it. You understand, right?
不过 光靠刀枪不能解决问题 你明白吗?
No, I don't!
我不明白!
Cloud, is this really about the fight?
克劳德 你打算开战吗?
Where are they?
他们去哪里?
The Forgotten City.
遗忘之都
Ajit.
他们老家
Please take care of it.
拜托你们
I have to talk to Rufus. Stop running!
我去和路法斯谈谈 你别逃避!
I know.
我明白
Even if you find the kids, you might not be able to help them.
就算找到孩子们可能也无能为力
Maybe something will happen that can never unhappen.
也有可能会造成无法挽回的结果
That scares you, doesn't it?
你害怕会变成这样 对吧?
But you need to think about now. Take it in.
不过请你面对更多的现实吧
You think you've got it hard? Tough.
很沉重吗? 因为沉重到无法承受了
Sharing your life with other people is hard.
学不会一个人生活就要学会忍耐
I know you don't want to be alone.
你明明很讨厌孤单 对吧?
You might not answer the phone, but you won't throw it away either.
虽然不接电话 但手机却从不离身吧
Why don't you just go to Ajit.
他们老家 你还不快去
Why do we have to lose out to our memory?
难道我们输给了回忆不成?
But I let you die.
那是因为我曾经见死不救啊
Really, you're always drifting
真是拖拖拉拉
Cloud, why can't you forgive yourself?
我说该是时候原谅自己了吧?
Are sins ever forgiven?
我的罪能被原谅吗?
I've never tried.
我没试过
Tried it?
试试看?
Tried it
试试看
Marlene, let's go home.
马琳 我们回家吧
I'm gonna try.
我去试试看
I'll let you know how it goes.
结果我会通知你
It's me, Reeve.
我是里布
How's work going?
工作的怎么样了?
I saw your flyer. How the hell do you stay in business?
我看过广告了 但那东西真能赚钱吗?
You never change, Cloud.
虽然那很适合 克劳德先生
I was thinking about helping you out,
但如果可以的话我也想帮忙 所以再连络
but I guess I'll call back another time.
有工作委托你
Later. Surprise! It's me, Yuffie.
超级大!工作完工后会去看马琳 帮我问后一下 拜了
So, hey, all the kids are missing from Wutai.
五台的孩子们失踪一事 你知道是怎么了吗
Have you heard anything? Give me a ring and fill me in, okay?
如果知道些事情的话 拜托你告诉我 好吗?
I never blamed you, not once.
你自己当心啊 我从不觉得你有对不起我
You came for me. That's all that matters.
你不是来了吗 这样就够了
Hey, are you listening? Why the hell are you doing this?
你们聋了?喂 装听不见啊 做这种事要干什么?
Denzel?
丹泽尔?
Denzel. Denzel!
丹泽尔 丹泽尔!
And what are we up to?
你们在干什么?
Mother's here, isn't she?
妈妈就在这儿吧?
How do you figure?
为什么?
This, what you call it?
这个叫什么呢?
Monument.
纪念碑
I bet Shinra made it.
是神罗做的
Wow, you used your head, didn't you?
所以说藏在这里?
Am I wrong?
不对吗?
Who knows.
不清楚
We don't know anything about it either.
我们也不知道
I see, as if anyone would trust you.
你看 果然是藏在某地
Rude!
鲁德!
Say something!
你来顶句话啊!
Does it hurt?
痛吗?
Yea.
嗯
But, not as bad as Denzel's.
不过没有丹泽尔那么痛
Can it be cure?
能治好吗?
I don't know.
不知道
For Denzel's sake, you've been trying so hard to find a cure for it.
你为了丹泽尔找遍了各种方法
You knew about that?
你怎么知道?
Cloud, you should cleanup your desk sometimes.
谁叫你从来不收拾桌子
I guess so.
说的也是
Say Cloud, because you can't fix Denzel's stigma,
克劳德是因为丹泽尔的星痕治不好
is that the reason why you left?
所以离家出走的?
Or is it because you had the stigma too?
还是因为自己也有了星痕?
I just thought I could take care for myself.
我 连自己都无法保护了
That's what I think.
你是那么想啊
How can you look after your family if you can't even take a good care of yourself.
无法保护自己的人 还谈什么保护家人
Or, at least that is what daddy would say.
我老爹说的
Cloud, don't give up.
克劳德 你别放弃
You, and Denzel, and Tifa always be there to help me.
马琳 丹泽尔 蒂法 总是在帮助我
You're always there whenever I needed you.
我总是被人保护着
For now, it's my turn.
这回要轮到我了
Sure.
嗯
Say, Kadaj. I've got a question for you.
呐 卡达裘 问你一件事
Just one question then.
仅此一件
You said you needed Jenova cells in order to return to what you were.
你说过要用杰诺娃细胞来能恢复原状
What does that mean?
那是什么意思?
He's coming back.
他会回来
Sephiroth.
萨菲罗斯
The nightmare.
噩梦啊
So they say.
好像是吧
You mean
好像是?
I don't know Sephiroth.
我跟萨菲罗斯没有瓜葛
But I know he's close.
只是对他有感觉
It gets under my skin.
真让人心烦
What if Mother loves him more than?
妈妈会选择我和萨菲罗斯哪一个呢?
Poor little remnants.
意念体真是可怜
It doesn't matter. You'll meet the same fate either way!
反正你们的下场只有一个!
Mother came to this planet after a long journey.
妈妈长途跋涉来到这个星球
To rid the cosmos of fools like you.
为了让愚蠢的家伙们灰飞烟灭
But you know about it as well.
不过你也很清楚吧
Nothing's changed since Mother came here.
这里和妈妈来的时候相比丝毫没改善
I have to change it. To make her happy.
所以我想让妈妈开心
There's nothing I wouldn't do, if she only asked. Hmph, the nightmare comes again, huh?
妈妈要我做什么 我就做什么 哼 噩梦再临是吗?
As long as you exist, the nightmares will come again and again.
你们一日不消失 就会重蹈覆辙
The Lifestream courses through our planet
星球上循环往复的生命之河
back and forth across the borders of life and death.
在生死之间徘徊而无阻
If that cycle is the very truth of life
如果生命的原貌就是这般周而复始
then history, too, will inevitably repeat itself.
那历史的重演也就是必然事件
So go on, bring your Jenovas and your Sephiroths.
杰诺娃也好 萨菲罗斯也好
It won't matter.
就随你们喜欢做吧
We'll do as life dictates
我们会听从命运的安排
and stop you every single time.
会一次又一次的阻止你们
Mr. President, is that an excuse for taking Mother?
社长 这就是你们抢走妈妈的藉口吗?
Don't tell me you're feeling remorse?
其实你该不会是很后悔吧?
Remorse?
后悔?
Why, I've never had this much fun.
我可是乐此不疲
Glad to hear that.
那再好不过
Now let's put an end to all this.
那么差不多也该结束了
Denzel, we've got to get away!
丹泽尔 快逃!
This is
这东西 算了吧
Is it coming after us?
它来没?
Why don't you go ask it?
没胆量看?
Having fun yet?
乐趣无穷啊?
Not at all!
无聊透顶啊!
Can't you guys just call it a day? !
你们有完没完?
We will.
不是说了吗
If you give back Mother, that'll be the end of everything.
只要把妈妈交出来 这一切就都结束了
Damned punks
废物
what do you need Jenova's head for?
你们拿杰诺娃的头做什么?
Forget your little Reunion and get a grip!
说什么再结合 吃错药了!
All we want is to be with Mother!
我们只不过是想见妈妈!
Mother will know what's best. She'll tell us what to do.
妈妈会决定今后的一切
Now, where is she?
那么妈妈在哪?
Mother, mother. It's Jenova's frigging head!
妈妈来妈妈去的 不就是杰诺娃的项上人头吗!
Hey! Don't talk about Mother like that.
喂!不许你这么称呼妈妈
Unforgiven!
饶不了你!
We're sorry
我错了
That's right
是啊
Wait, why are we apologizing?
干嘛要道歉啊
Tifa?
蒂法?
Bastard!
你这混蛋!
You look after Mom.
在这儿保护你妈
Barret!
巴雷特
Marlene's safe, right? Huh?
马琳还好好的吧 啊?
I can't match this!
打不过啊!
Who's using my materia? !
谁动了我的魔石球?!
The bad guys, naturally.
不用问 当然是坏人
Dammit!
可恶!
Who's that?
谁啊?
The latest model, Sierra!
新型的希艾拉号!
I'll let you ride it later!
待会儿让你们坐坐!
Where's the phone shop?
手机店在哪里?
Who's that person?
他呢?
These are our friends.
都是同伴
Denzel, can you make it to the bar?
丹泽尔 能一个人跑回店里吗?
Enough!
有完没完!
Tifa!
蒂法!
Denzel!
丹泽尔!
Cloud!
克劳德!
I'm sorry I'm a little late.
抱歉 我来晚了
It's alright.
没关系的
Are you alright?
没事吧?
Marlene's safe. I took her home.
马琳很安全 我把她留在了店里
It feels a little lighter.
我觉得轻松多了
Maybe I wore it down by dragging it along so much.
总拖来拖去 拖轻了包袱
I'm going back to the bar. I'll be waiting with Marlene.
我一个人回店里吧 跟马琳等你们
You're gonna come home, right, Cloud?
克劳德也会回家吧?
I can do this!
谁会输给你啊!
You're late dammit!
你来的太晚了!
Isn't this fun Boss? What should we summon next?
太愉快了 社长 接下来召唤什么好呢?
Mother? A good son would have known.
妈妈?该早点发现啊 不肖子
Go, Cloud!
宰了它 克劳德!
Haiya!
去吧!
Fly!
飞吧!
It's not over yet!
还早着呢!
Here!
去吧!
Mother!
妈妈!
Boss! Boss!
社长!社长!
Boss!
社长!
You mess up with the wrong guy.
打架不要找错人啊
Rude!
鲁德!
This is bad! This is bad! This is bad yo!
不好不好!大事不好!
Ooh, Rude. You're alright.
噢 鲁德 你没事啊
Yea.
是
I'm just peachy.
其实很有事
Senpai!
前辈!
Hey, partner.
我说搭档
This thing got any bite?
这个很厉害吗?
Shinra technology at its finest.
凝聚了神罗的科技与汗水
Oh, so you made this.
你研发的吗?
I don't know about the power, but it sure is flashy.
威力姑且不说 华丽得很
Ohhoh!
喂喂!
You like that, don't you, partner?
喜欢吧 搭档?
No overtime tonight, eh?
看来今天不用加班了
Mother!
妈妈!
Mother
妈妈
Mother!
妈妈!
Let's go, Cloud.
我们走 克劳德
I've finally found Mother.
我终于见到妈妈了
So, what happens now?
接下来做什么?
Mother will tell me, you'll see.
妈妈会告诉我的
I guess a remnanets won't know anything.
意念体一无所知吗
So what if I'm a puppet.
反正我是傀儡
You used to be no different!
和过去的你没什么两样!
Cloud, I brought you materia!
克劳德 魔石球在此!
Don't shake it! Yo, Cid! Land this junk heap.
别摇晃啊!希德!快降落
Shut up! You want off, you jump!
吵死了!自己不会跳啊 跳!
Let them fight by themselves.
别插手
Kadaj is an avatar of Sephiroth.
他是萨菲罗斯的意念体
Think of him as a sort of larval form.
好比是幼虫
Larva? You mean he's some kinda insect?
幼虫 虫子 他是虫子啊?
Calm down, Princess!
小姑娘 安静点!
So that punk's gonna become Sephiroth?
早晚变身成萨菲罗斯吗?
Wait, Cloud, does he know that?
你说 克劳德知道这事吗?
Probably.
恐怕知道
I see.
是吗
Let's leave them alone.
嗯 让他一个人战斗吧
I don't get it! Someone explain it to me!
我不明白!谁来说明一下!
This is man talk.
男人才会知道
Sexist. Sexist!
性别歧视 大男子主义!
Will you calm down, Princess! ?
小姑娘 闭上嘴
Some of the men ain't following either.
是男人也不懂
Two years ago During our last battle do you remember what it was like to be strong?
2年前 最终决战的时候明明有过的斗志?
It's only been two years but somehow that strength has slipped away
却被短短的两年时间冲淡了
I think Cloud's found it again though.
我想克劳德又点燃了斗志
I'll give him 10 minutes.
切 那就等他10分钟吧
Always a pain in the ass, that Cloud.
克劳德还是一样那么难伺候
At least he's honest.
这叫坦率
I'll show you my Reunion.
我的再结合 让你好好见识
It's been a while, Cloud.
久违了啊 克劳德
Your stigma is gone?
星痕消失了吗?
How unfortunate.
很可惜
Just what do you really want?
你到底期望什么?
The ghosts of geostigma victims.
死在星痕之下的亡魂
They will rejoin the Lifestream and circle the planet
它和生命之河一起围绕着星球
Eventually it infringes on the planet
早晚侵蚀星球
What I really want, Cloud
克劳德 我的愿望是
is to sail the darkness of the cosmos with this planet as my vessel
以星球作舟 向宇宙的黑暗启航
just as my mother did long ago.
就如当年的妈妈
Then one day we'll find a new planet
我们早晚会找到新的星球
and on its soil we'll create a shining future.
在新的天地创造光辉的未来
What will happen to this planet?
我们的星球会怎样?
Well, that's up to you to decide.
谁知道 看你的本事了
Sister?
姐姐?
Where did you find this strength?
哦?什么使你变强了?
I don't feel like telling you.
懒得和你说
I've thought of a wonderful present for you.
我一直考虑该送什么给你
Shall I give you despair?
送你绝望如何?
Kneel. Beg for forgiveness.
跪下吧 让我看看你请求饶恕的模样
Is this the pain you felt before, Cloud?
当年的痛苦你可还记得? 克劳德
Let me remind you again, And this time, engraved into your memory.
现在赐给你更刻骨铭心的痛吧
What do you treasure most?
对你而言什么最重要?
I want the joy of taking it from you.
让我夺来快乐一下吧
So, what if they look hopeless?
换做是我 绝对不放弃?
If it were me, I still wouldn't give up.
即便情形很绝望
Embrace your dreams.
握紧你的梦想
Also, whatever happen protect your honor as a SOLDIER.
时刻与战士的荣耀同在
You never made as a SOLDIER.
你虽没成为战士
But it's the feeling that count, the feeling.
但也不妨抱着那颗心
Zacks.
扎克斯
Well, do you need a help there?
要我帮你一把?
You already beat him once didn't you? This should be an easy one, right?
你的手下败将而已 轻松搞定他 对吧?
Yea.
是啊
Never forget.
别再忘了
I am
我是
the proof that you existed.
你生命的见证
How sad. You who understand nothing.
可悲啊 你根本什么都不懂
There is nothing I don't treasure!
所有的一切都很重要!
Stay in my memories where you belong.
在回忆中安息吧
I will never be a memory.
我 不会成为回忆
Brother
哥哥
Kadaj?
卡达裘?
You can let it go now, if you want.
也该放弃努力了
Mother, is that you?
是妈妈吗?
Everyone's waiting, if you're ready to go.
回大家身边吧
He did it! That's how it goes!
怎么样 知道厉害了吧!我说的没错吧!
A man! Cloudsan's a man!
男子汉!克劳德真是个男子汉!
See? Just like I told you. He can do anything if he puts his mind to it.
看到了?克劳德想做就能成功
Hold on tight, you guys!
你们几个抓稳了!
You were always with us, weren't you?
你一直 都在我们身边吧?
Thank you.
谢谢
Let's all go home together.
一起回家吧
And play with everyone
大家一起玩吧
Cloud!
克劳德!
Cloud said he'd come home.
克劳德也会回家吧
Let's go.
我们走
Mom?
妈妈?
Why does everyone keep calling me that?
又来了 这是他第几次叫我妈妈了?
I guess they must be fond of you.
他这么想念你有什么关系
I think this one's outgrown me.
我可不要这么大的孩子
Tough luck, friend. Looks like your place isn't here.
很可惜你不属于这里
She said to wait here for Cloud.
姐姐说克劳德会来这里
Welcome home.
欢迎回来
Im home.
我回来了
There are still children with the stigma.
一些孩子还留有星痕
Okay, it's time to get fixed up.
去吧 让他帮你治好
It's okay.
可以放心了
Be strong.
加油
Last one in is a rotten egg! It worked, it worked!
都给我跳进去洗澡!治好了 治好了!
You're all right now, aren't you?
以后 没问题了吧?
Yeah. I'm not alone.
我 并不孤单
Whose grave is this?
这里是谁的坟墓?
No.
不
This is where the "hero" began his journey.
这里是英雄开始旅程的地方